[♪♪♪]
[RUMBLING]
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[SNAPS]
[RUMBLING]
AKI: Every night, the same dream,
the same strange planet.
But why?
What are they trying to tell me?
It's been 34 years
since they arrived on this planet.
And not a day passes
that the survivors,
forced to live in barrier cities,
do not live in fear.
I have vowed to end that fear.
I believe my dreams hold the key.
The question is, will I be
in time to save the Earth?
[♪♪♪]
[ENGINES STOP]
Where are you?
[BEEPS]
[PHANTOMS MOANING]
[AKI GASPS]
[PHANTOM SCREECHES]
[GROWLING]
[AKI PANTING]
[BEEPS]
[PHANTOM GROWLING]
[GRUNTS]
[SCREECHING]
GRAY:
This is a restricted area.
Do not move!
RYAN:
What's she doing here, captain?
GRAY: I don't know,
but we're getting her out.
You're coming with us.
AKI: Behind you !
[SCREECHING]
GRAY:
Hold it right there!
Damn it. Let's move, people!
RYAN:
Two coming through the east wall !
NEIL: Sarge, hold your fire.
Those tanks are flammable!
[BOTH GRUNT]
GRAY:
Ryan, Neil, let's go!
GRAY: Just what the hell
do you think you're doing?
There's a life form in here.
There hasn't been life here in years.
Well, there is now.
Life form or not,
I'm taking you in.
Fine, arrest me. But I'm not
leaving without that life form.
RYAN:
It's gonna one of those days.
[BEEPING]
JANE:
Captain, the transport is not
going to wait for us much longer.
GRAY:
I understand that.
It's in bad shape.
RYAN:
Oh, please, tell me we're not
risking our necks for this plant!
JANE: I wouldn't even
call it a plant, it's a weed.
NEIL: I wouldn't even call it a weed.
I need a minute to extract it.
NEIL:
Miss, that's a minute we do not have.
RYAN: I'm afraid he's right
about that, ma'am.
NEIL:
Phantoms. We have incoming.
RYAN:
Captain, we need to get out of here.
GRAY:
Understood, sergeant.
RYAN: Could you hurry, miss?
AKI: Done.
NEIL: Captain?
GRAY: Yes, Neil?
NEIL: Just so you know, I agree
with the "let's get out of here" thing.
GRAY:
Duly noted.
JANE: Can I have this,
please? Thank you.
We're surrounded !
JANE: No shit!
GRAY: Everybody, just relax.
JANE: We gotta get to higher ground.
GRAY:
Everyone, up top!
Go, go, go!
[PHANTOMS SCREECHING]
GRAY: Requesting immediate evac.
PILOT [OVER RADIO]: Affirmative.
NEIL:
Up here!
[PHANTOM GROWLS]
JANE: Captain ! Captain, come on !
RYAN: They're right behind you !
JANE:
I've got you !
JANE: You okay?
GRAY: Yeah.
NEIL:
All right, everybody, here they come.
[PHANTOMS SCREECHING]
Phew! You okay?
You're gonna be all right.
[HELMET CLICKS]
GRAY:
Can you give me one good reason
why shouldn't I arrest you?
I am Dr. Aki Ross.
I have clearance to be here.
GRAY:
Not unlimited clearance.
And now without authorization.
AKI: Listen, captain,
I don't have time for this.
GRAY:
Do you realize you've just risked
the lives of my squad and me?
Look, I don't wanna talk about it.
The fact of the matter is,
it was worth the lives
of you and your men.
"You and your men"?
She thinks you're a man.
I think she's an idiot.
NEIL: I know you're not a man.
I think you're an idiot too.
NEIL: Very funny.
GRAY: Well, I do wanna talk about it.
Did it ever occur to you
that maybe we would've
volunteered to risk our lives
had we been given a choice?
Well, nobody asked you
to save me.
I don't believe this.
You have not changed a bit!
Gray?
Yeah. Nice to see you too.
[♪♪♪]
[ALARM SOUNDING]
MAN: Welcome back, captain.
GRAY: We're clean.
MAN: Let's make
sure of that, shall we?
NEIL:
I hate getting scanned.
Sir, these scanners are probably
worse for us than the Phantoms.
No "probably" about it, captain.
These machines are suspected
of causing sterility.
And I want to have a little
Neil Jr. calling me "daddy"
someday.
That's a spooky
thought.
Why are you always
busting my chops?
People, let's just do
this thing, all right?
Yes, sir.
JANE: Yes, sir.
NEIL: Yes, sir.
Okay, next.
Looks like you've
gained some weight.
It's called upper-body strength,
Neil. Get a girlfriend.
I'm working on it.
You know, my security rating
allows me to bypass this.
Not today it doesn't.
Something's not right.
About this mission? Or that woman?
Both.
MAN:
Next.
Listen, captain,
I think--
I don't care
what you think, doctor.
You're getting scanned
just like everybody else.
[GASPS]
RYAN:
Aw, shit!
JANE: Captain.
NEIL: They got him.
There must be a mistake.
You came in contact
with a Phantom, sir.
Please remain calm.
Administering treatment shield.
What level is he?
Blue. Code red in 31/2 minutes.
[♪♪♪]
We have to treat him. Now.
I'm sorry, but that's impossible.
We'll transfer him
to the treatment center.
There's no time for that.
Get him to the table.
RYAN:
Hang in there, captain.
Locating pathogens.
NEIL:
Jesus, look at that thing !
How much more time?
Not enough. When he reaches
code red, the treatment shield won't
be able to hold the alien particles.
AKI:
Engaging bio-etheric laser.
What's going on?
Where'd it go?
RYAN:
What the hell is going on?
MAN: We've lost contact.
Infestation is moving deeper.
Tracking.
MAN: There's no time.
MAN: There is no time!
You're gonna lose him !
[COUGHS]
MAN:
His treatment shield is failing.
Found it.
Come on.
[GROWLING]
[SCREECHES]
[♪♪♪]
It's all right.
Don't worry, you'll be back
to normal in no time.
Doctor, we need
to scan you for infestation.
That won't be necessary.
I'll take responsibility.
Hey, doc.
Thanks for saving him.
Are you all right?
AKI: Yeah, but the military's
impounded my ship.
What's with her?
What's with her and the captain?
What's with her
and that stupid plant?
What?
Forward me the Phantom data
and everything regarding the five
spirits collected so far.
Yes, doctor.
Spirits? I thought we weren't
supposed to use the "s" word.
[CHUCKLES]
Don't get smart with me.
Now let's see if
that plant does the trick.
[♪♪♪]
It's a match.
We've found it.
SID:
Yes.
The sixth spirit.
Your little scene today
broke nearly every protocol.
How long do you think this would
have survived outside the barrier?
Aki, you know there are elements in
the council and military just waiting
for an excuse to shut us down.
Look, 20 years ago,
who discovered this energy
in the Phantoms? You.
And who proved
the same energy source
existed in humans
and every life form?
You. You made it possible
to harness that energy
for ovo-pacs, scanners,
even the barrier.
The council knows that.
They trust you. Doctor,
we're so close to proving--
But we still need this part,
and this one here.
Exactly. Two more pieces
and we've solved the puzzle!
And we need to be free
to find those pieces.
I want to show you
something, Aki.
What is this?
Read.
"All life is born of Gaia
and each life has a spirit.
Each new spirit is housed
in a physical body."
Doctor--
Go on.
"Through their experiences on Earth,
each spirit matures and grows.
When the physical body dies,
the mature spirit, enriched by
its life on Earth, returns to Gaia,
bringing with it
the experiences
enabling Gaia
to live and grow."
It's my old diary.
I wrote that 43 years ago,
when I was the age you
are now.
Dr. Sid !
SID: Remember what
happened to Galileo?
They threw him in jail
because
he said the Earth was not
the center of the universe.
That could happen to us.
Our ideas are unpopular, Aki.
If you have any notes or records
that could be used against you,
destroy them.
Keep them up here.
Right.
And stay away from
your friend the captain.
He saves your life,
you save his life,
this leads to that.
I was young once too,
you know.
Doctor, there is a war going on.
No one's young
anymore.
[RUMBLING]
[GASPS]
[SIGHS]
MAN 1: Ladies and gentlemen
of the council,
could you please
explain why?
Zeus was completed
a month ago.
If we attack the meteor
with this, we will eliminate
the Phantoms
at their source.
MAN 2: General Hein, calm down.
At our last meeting,
we voted six to two
to postpone using the Zeus cannon
to attack the Leonid Meteor.
We have reconvened today
to vote on that very issue again.
Now, I'd like to ask the director of
the Bio-Etheric Center to speak.
Dr. Sid, please.
Thank you. Ahem.
As you all know, the Phantoms'
nest is in the Leonid Meteor
that landed here 34 years ago.
What you see now are the records of
every assault on the meteor to date.
Physical attacks have had
utterly no effect.
This scene took place
three months ago during
a full-scale bombardment.
Now, please note the Phantoms
outside the meteor are indeed
destroyed.
However, inside, many that
were dormant come to life,
and as you see,
overall Phantom density
remains the same.
The newly risen aliens
respond to the attack
by burrowing even
deeper into the Earth.
Now, this is very
interesting to me, Dr. Sid,
because we see
the same thing during surgery
when using bio-etheric lasers
on Phantom particles, do we not?
Yes, indeed we do.
You see, the injured
particles escape,
burying or digging themselves
deeper into a patient's body.
And when we increase
the laser power to destroy
these deeper particles,
we have had incidents resulting
in further injury to a patient,
and in some cases, death.
And what exactly
does that mean, doctor?
It means there's
a very good chance
the beam from the Zeus cannon will
burn the Phantoms in the meteor.
Exactly! Thank you.
However, it also means that
the beam energy may be too
strong, injuring the Earth.
Injure the Earth?
You mean the Gaia.
SID: I mean--
You mean the spirit of the Earth.
[♪♪♪]
Yes, the spirit of the Earth.
[COUNCIL MEMBERS
MURMURING]
Did he just say
what I think he said?
What are you doing?
I know what I'm doing.
And whatever you do,
keep your mouth shut.
HEIN:
This is ridiculous.
Doctor, with all due respect,
did you come here just to talk
about some Gaia theory?
To tell us that
the planet is alive?
That it has a spirit?
That's a fairy tale, doctor.
And I'm sorry, but we don't
have time for that.
It is not a fairy tale.
It is true.
Ah. Oh.
So if I point a gun
at the Earth and fire,
I'm not just making a hole in
the ground, I'm killing the planet.
Dr. Sid, the Gaia theory
has not been proven.
Even if Gaia does exist,
won't we still have to
remove the Phantoms?
I think if there's any chance
of success, we should take it.
Don't you agree?
Of course I do.
But there is an alternative
to the space cannon.
Another method?
SID: Yes, a means of
disabling the Phantoms.
Please.
As we know, the aliens display
a distinct energy pattern.
Now, it is a fact that two
opposing bio-etheric waves
placed one over the other
will cancel each other out.
It is theoretically possible
to construct a wave pattern
in direct opposition
to the Phantom energy.
We are currently assembling
such a wave and are nearing
completion.
Members of the council,
gathering plants and animals
from around the world
to fight the Phantoms
is utter nonsense.
The Zeus cannon is a proven,
effective weapon.
It will kill Phantoms.
Can we afford to wait
for some crazy invention,
some army of touchy-feely
plants and animals,
an invention that offers
no solid evidence that it
will destroy the aliens?
There is evidence!
Our partially completed
energy wave
has successfully stopped
Phantom particles from spreading
through a terminally
infected patient.
Doctor, do you claim to
have evidence that a terminal
patient has been cured?
Not cured. The wave
is not complete.
But we've succeeded
in containing the particles
safely inside the patient.
Ugh. Where is the proof?
Here.
[BEEPS]
[COUNCIL MEMBERS
GASPING AND CHATTERING]
SID:
You may have bought us some time,
Aki, but I wonder at what cost.
Doctor, I can't keep
hiding in the background
while you protect me.
I want what life I have left
to mean something.
You listen to me. When we find
the seventh and eighth spirits--
If we find them.
What we need now
is some luck.
Luck has nothing
to do with it.
Faith and hard work, girl,
because I'll be damned
if you're going to die before me.
[DOOR OPENS]
The council decided
to postpone firing
the Zeus cannon.
I guess I put on
a good show.
Mind if I tag along?
You'll probably get bored.
[MAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY
OVER SPEAKER]
So, what are you doing?
[WOMAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY
OVER SPEAKER]
GRAY:
Oh, I see. You're giving me
the silent treatment.
I'm scanning the city
for the seventh spirit.
RYAN:
Hurry up, Neil.
NEIL: Relax, sarge. I've almost got it.
What do you think you're doing?
We're just gonna
strand them for a while.
Hey, don't look at me,
it was his idea.
This was your idea?
We're just helping
the captain out a little.
Yeah, come on, Jane.
Where's your sense
of romance?
You've seen how
the captain looks at her.
[GRUNTS]
It's amore, baby.
What's going on?
GRAY:
It's probably just a glitch.
Listen, Aki--
Ah, I'm still mad at you.
You're mad at me?
Leaving your helmet on.
Not telling me who you were.
That doesn't seem a little childish?
Hey, well, I was just upset when
you just packed up and left for the
Zeus Station without saying a word.
Well, now you know what
was going on, all right?
Yeah. Now I know.
My operation had to be
done in zero grav, okay?
Fine.
And how about the fact that
I was sent there on a job
and you wouldn't even see me?
I was probably helping Dr. Sid
collect spirit waves.
Well, now I know.
So I'm sorry!
Well, me too!
So we're both sorry.
[BOTH SIGH]
So will you tell me
about them?
About what?
About the spirits
you've collected.
[♪♪♪]
I was infected by a Phantom
during an experiment.
Normally, no one
could have survived.
How did you?
Dr. Sid created a membrane
around the infection,
keeping me alive.
So the first spirit wave
was me.
The second was a fish.
A fish?
The third was a deer I found
in a wildlife preserve outside
Moscow.
The fourth was a bird.
Ever tried to track a sparrow
from outer space? It's no fun.
What am I saying?
You probably would love that.
I probably would.
And then there was that plant
I collected from Times Square.
I thought that was number six.
What?
You skipped one.
The fifth was a little girl dying
in a hospital emergency room.
I retrieved the sample
in time, but she. . .
I told her everything had a spirit:
Dogs, cats, trees, little girls.
Even the Earth.
I told her that she wasn't dying,
just returning to the Earth's spirit,
to Gaia.
She, uh, told me that
she was ready to die.
She said I didn't have to make up
stories to make her feel better.
Only 7 years old and ready to die.
I'm sorry.
I have work to do. I have to find
the seventh and eighth spirits.
Don't, please.
You don't believe
any of this, do you?
I just don't know, Aki.
Is this why
you shut me out?
You should have told me.
I don't know how much
time I have left.
Who does?
[ELEVATOR STARTS]
I better get back to scanning.
[MAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY
OVER SPEAKER]
[♪♪♪]
[CLEARS THROAT]
Captain Edwards,
you extracted a Dr. Ross from
Old New York several days ago,
did you not?
Yes, sir.
What were your impressions of her?
She seemed very capable
and determined, sir.
You and the Deep Eyes are
being temporarily reassigned.
You will guard Dr. Ross when
she reenters the wasteland.
GRAY:
Understood, sir.
You don't understand yet,
captain.
Report any aberrant behavior
in Dr. Ross to the major immediately.
Aberrant behavior, sir?
The woman carries
an alien infestation, captain.
We don't know what
it may be doing to her.
The alien presence could be
affecting her judgment.
They may be manipulating
the doctor for their very own
purposes.
Is the general suggesting
that Dr. Ross is a spy?
The general is wondering why
he's explaining himself to a captain.
She's had prolonged exposure
to Phantom tissue.
If this begins to manifest
itself in any way,
Dr. Ross is to be placed
under arrest and transported
here for observation.
It is, in fact, for her
own good, captain.
Of course, sir.
Major, send some of our men
to keep an eye on the good captain.
[♪♪♪]
[METAL CLINKING]
AKI:
I'm convinced that these dreams
are some form of communication.
Their message still eludes me,
but they're coming faster now
and that can only mean one thing.
The Phantoms inside me
are beginning to win.
JANE: Our target is 50 klicks
west of Tucson.
NEIL [OVER RADIO]: Roger.
Phantom concentration?
Not good. We've got
big metas everywhere.
So it's gonna be
a real picnic.
Stick close to me.
No heroics today, okay?
Everything by the book.
By the book. Right.
If we drop energy buoys
here, here and here,
we should be able to land,
acquire the target and get out
before the Phantoms
even know we were there.
And the buoys will
attract the Phantoms?
JANE: Yeah.
For a while.
So you're from the 307th?
Under General Hein?
Ever done wasteland recon
before? It can get pretty ugly.
[♪♪♪]
[GROWLING]
NEIL [OVER RADIO]:
Captain, rendezvous for evac
at vector 6, coordinate 279.
GRAY [OVER RADIO]:
Roger that. Stay alert for hostiles.
[PHANTOMS GROWLING]
GRAY:
Looks like they've taken the bait.
The seventh spirit should be
just beyond that line of wreckage.
I don't see how any living thing
could survive out here.
We'll find out
soon enough.
RYAN: This was the Phantom
Cleansing Mission.
It was supposed to end the war.
My father's in
here somewhere.
All right.
Let's move out,
people.
[BIRD CHIRPING]
I'll be damned.
A survivor.
GRAY:
What's it doing out here?
Hoping for life to return.
RYAN:
Is that our spirit, doc?
No.
AKI:
We're closing in on the life form.
GRAY: Distance?
Hard to say. We're very close.
I don't see anything.
[BEEPING]
You're not gonna tell me it's him?
That's impossible.
[♪♪♪]
It's not the soldier,
it's his ovo-pac.
How do you explain that?
The pacs power our weapons,
the barrier cities. . .
I mean, it's just
bio-etheric energy.
And to create that energy
we use living tissue.
Single-cell organisms.
You're telling me
his backpack is
the seventh spirit?
Yes.
NEIL [OVER RADIO]:
We have incoming. Captain?
Do you read me?
GRAY:
Say again?
Do you read me, captain?
We have incoming.
Ryan, get the soldier's pac.
[PHANTOMS SCREECHING
AND ROARING]
[PHANTOM SCREECHES]
I need a hand ! Sarge!
Those buoys? They're not working.
Yeah. Thank you.
[PANTING]
Are you all right?
Of course I am.
GRAY:
Let's get the hell out of here!
Something's not right.
This shouldn't be happening.
Something's attracting them.
Aki !
They're right on us, sir,
closing in fast!
Jane, take the lead.
[WEAPON POWERING UP]
Fire in the hole!
GRAY:
Get us out of here, Neil.
Sir, I would love to, but--
GRAY [OVER RADIO]: Just do it!
[COMPUTER VOICE
SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Sir?
Okay, that's it.
RYAN: That doesn't
look good, captain.
We have to get her to a hospital.
SOLDIER:
You have your orders, sir.
What the hell's
going on here?
SOLDIER:
Dr. Ross is to be taken
into custody now, sir.
Lower your weapons.
That's an order!
Sir, we have not choice
but to relieve you of your command.
I won't let you do this, soldier.
You'll have to shoot me.
Stand down, captain !
[♪♪♪]
[EXPLOSIONS]
[GASPS]
GRAY:
Aki !
NEIL [OVER RADIO]:
Hang on, everyone!
SOLDIER: That's enough.
Hands where I can see them.
Everyone, now!
NEIL:
Deep Eyes, hard to starboard !
Neil, get us back
to New York, fast!
[♪♪♪]
ELLIOT:
The Deep Eyes are returning
from the wasteland, sir.
Apparently, there was an incident.
Mm-hm.
It would seem the Phantoms
were attracted to Dr. Ross.
The crew barely escaped
with their lives. And, sir,
Captain Edwards
is still in command.
Issue an order.
I want Edwards and Dr. Ross
placed under arrest.
All research materials pertaining
to Dr. Sid's wave theory
are to be confiscated
immediately.
That might not go over
too well with the council, sir.
Oh, what a tragedy
that would be.
This is perfect, major.
The good captain has
opened the door for us.
By tomorrow morning,
the council will be at our feet,
thanking us for exposing
the traitors in our midst
and imploring us
to save them
from the Phantoms.
How is she, doctor?
She is dying.
There must be something
you can do.
SID: Aki is fighting with
only six of the eight spirits.
We'll have to implant the seventh
directly into her chest plate.
It took a bullet.
I think it might be damaged.
SID: We have to repair
this panel quickly.
Her vital signs are dropping.
Aki is slipping away from us.
She needs a sympathetic spirit
to help hold her in this world.
And I can think of no spirit
better suited for that task
than yours, captain.
I don't understand.
You don't have to understand.
You just be with her now.
You keep her here with us.
[♪♪♪]
Aki? Where are we?
On an alien planet.
How is that possible?
I'm not entirely sure.
You seem pretty calm.
I've been having this dream
every night for months.
Dream?
Well, whatever it is.
You're really here,
aren't you?
What's happening
to me?
Dr. Sid is implanting the seventh
spirit directly into your body.
Then you're my spiritual support.
Gray, how sweet of you.
Look, I don't think you realize
how serious this situation is.
Something you
should see here, sir.
And I am watching
what, major?
It seems Dr. Ross has been
recording her dreams.
HEIN:
And why would I be interested in. . .
her dreams?
This is it.
This is our evidence.
She's under the influence
of the Phantoms.
Dr. Ross' dreams should be
all the council needs to authorize
the firing of the Zeus cannon.
The council is content to hide,
cowering inside this barrier,
while the world dies
a little more every day.
I believe they need a push
in the right direction, major.
Get together a group
of your most trusted men.
[♪♪♪]
What are they doing?
Why are they staring at us?
Not at us.
Welcome back, captain.
Is it over?
How is she, doctor?
She's gonna be fine.
But this is only temporary.
We'll need to find the eighth
and final spirit to cure her.
Aki, can you hear me?
I finished it.
I know what it means.
I know what the Phantoms
really are.
POLICEMAN: Nobody move!
You're all under arrest!
[DOOR OPENS]
ELLIOT:
We have them, sir.
Sir?
HEIN:
My wife and daughter. . .
[DOOR CLOSES]
were killed by Phantoms when
the San Francisco Barrier City
was attacked.
Did I ever tell you that?
I try to imagine what
that must have been like,
seeing everyone around you fall
over dead for no apparent reason.
And then, at the end,
feeling something next to you,
invisible,
touching you,
reaching inside your body. . .
You've lost family,
haven't you?
Yes, sir.
That's why I trust you.
All of you.
You know what must be done.
COMPUTER:
Security override.
Perimeter breach.
[TECHNICIANS CHATTERING]
Major, arrest these men.
Take it easy. Take it easy.
Stand up. Let's go.
GUARD: You are relieved of
your post. Don't ask questions.
Reduce power to Sector 31.
Sir, you do realize
that the Phantoms--
What I realize, major,
is that we must force
the council to take action
against the enemy.
GUARD 1:
Twenty-five percent of
energy pipe alpha redirected.
GUARD 2: Lowering power
output to Sector 31.
Barrier breach
in Sector 31, general.
They're coming
through now.
Oh, I think we can easily
handle a few Phantoms
in a contained space.
Relax, major. When this night's over,
you're going to be a hero.
GRAY:
Aki, I don't--
AKI: But you were in my
dream, Gray. You saw it.
That's just it. I'm not sure
what I saw. How can you be?
Captain, please,
let her continue.
All right, why do you think
we've never been able to
determine
a relationship between the human-
sized Phantoms and the giant ones
roaming the wastelands?
Excuse me, doc,
but what frigging relationship?
I mean, you got your human-sized
Phantoms, and your creepy
caterpillary Phantoms,
and your flying Phantoms,
and let's not forget my
personal favorite,
the big, fat, giant Phantoms.
Down, boy.
He's right. If you spent
as much time in the field
as we have,
you know there is no relationship.
It's like a zoo out there.
Precisely, I think the giant ones
are like our whales or elephants.
But why would an invading army
bring a bunch of whales and
elephants along for the ride?
Unless their ship was some
kind of a crazy Noah's Ark?
Hmm. We have always
assumed that the meteor
was intended as
a form of transportation.
Perhaps it wasn't.
The meteor is a chunk of their
planet that got thrown into space
when they destroyed their world.
But how could they survive
the trip across outer space
on a hunk of rock?
They didn't.
Whoa. This is all
beginning to make a
creepy kind of sense.
What do you think
about all this, captain?
I think that explains why
we never had a chance.
All our strategies are based
on one assumption:
That we were fighting
alien invaders.
Think of the dream, Gray.
How they died.
Since then, all they've
known is suffering.
They're not an invading army.
They're ghosts.
How many Phantoms?
ELLIOT: More than enough
to convince the council, sir.
Excellent. Sound an alert. Send
a squad out to eliminate them.
Yes, sir.
Alert status.
Full deployment.
Sir, I have numerous
Phantom contacts!
Well, of course you do.
Outside of Sector 31, sir,
and moving at incredible speed.
Major, what the hell
is going on here?
They're in the pipes.
They're moving with
the bio-etheric energy flow.
That's impossible.
No living thing could
survive in those pipes.
ELLIOT:
Well, we've got a big one
heading this way. Meta class, sir.
[PHANTOM GROWLING]
Oh, my God.
Hold your fire!
[ELLIOT GRUNTING]
[ELECTRICITY CRACKLING]
[RUMBLING]
What have I done?
[EXPLOSIONS]
GRAY: Come on, Neil.
We need to find a way out.
Now, you're our man. Think.
Captain, these walls are
titanium alloy and the bars
are pulse-sonic lasers.
I mean, it's not like I can
just wave a magic wand and. . .
Whoa.
[ALARM WAILING]
Neil, I'm impressed.
That makes two of us.
COMPUTER:
Proceed to the nearest
evacuation facility.
I think we should proceed
to the nearest evacuation facility.
Proceed to the nearest
evacuation--
COMPUTER:
Proceed to the nearest
evacuation facility.
[EXPLOSION]
[PHANTOM GROWLING]
GRAY: Here they come.
AKI: But the others! Dr. Sid !
Deep Eyes'll take care
of him. Come on.
[PHANTOM SNARLING]
[♪♪♪]
AKI: What's happening?
Why can we see them now?
They must be carrying
a residual charge from
passing through the barrier.
Behind you !
COMPUTER:
Please stand clear of the door.
[PHANTOMS GROWLING
AND WAILING]
All aboard,
captain !
[♪♪♪]
[PEOPLE SHOUTING]
[MAN YELLING]
[PEOPLE SCREAMING]
We need to find my ship.
If it was towed inside the city,
it would be in the military hangar.
That's a big "if."
[♪♪♪]
Look out!
[TIRES SCREECHING]
Get us onto the platform.
You got it.
[PHANTOM GROWLING]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
Okay, now what?
We're going through the station.
What?
Captain, with all
due respect--
Excuse me, captain.
The station.
We're going through it.
It's the only way.
So I gather this will be
somewhat of a rough ride?
Doc, you've got a talent
for understatement.
Hang on, everybody!
Doc?
Interesting.
Anybody hurt?
Captain.
[♪♪♪]
Oh, God. Talk to me, sarge.
Ouch !
Give me a hand, Jane.
JANE: Right.
No, wait. We're risking
further injury. We need the
proper tools to cut him out.
They're in
my ship.
No. No, doc. No drugs.
Captain?
You heard the man.
We'll find the ship
and be back for you.
I'll stay with him.
NEIL: Me too.
Nobody's staying.
Just give me a gun.
You got it.
Give him a weapon. Do it!
We'll be back for you,
sergeant.
You hear me?
I hear you, captain.
Now, get out of here.
Let's move out.
A quad-axle ATV.
This is good.
It can be used to retrieve Ryan
and transport him safely here.
However, we'll need to
replace these spent fuel cells.
There could be some live
ovo-pacs in the hangar.
All right, Jane, check the hangar.
Neil, get us ready for takeoff.
Aki and Dr. Sid,
prep the Quatro.
I'll go to the tower
and rotate the airtray.
This city may be lost, but we
are not. Let's do this thing
and get the hell out of here.
[♪♪♪]
Gray, be careful.
You too.
[MOANING IN DISTANCE]
[GRUNTING]
Oh, yeah.
GRAY [OVER RADIO]:
Neil, do you read me?
Loud and clear, captain.
This baby'll fly itself.
[LIFT DOCKS]
Flight path is set.
Beginning rotation.
Whoa, stop the airtray.
We have a problem.
I'm reading an impound tractor is
still attached to the prow of the ship.
Can you disengage it
from the cockpit?
No, sir. Permission to go outside
and detach the coupling.
GRAY:
Do it.
There's the problem.
[BEEPING]
The controls are locked,
naturally.
Jane, let me ask you something.
You think we're gonna get out
of here alive?
I mean, I wonder if anybody
else has gotten out.
You think anyone's
made it this far? Huh?
You think this eighth-spirit stuff
is really gonna work against
the Phantoms?
I mean, what if it's all
a bunch of mumbo-jumbo?
Ow! Jeez.
Jane, do you mind if we stop talking?
I'm trying to concentrate here.
[WAILING IN DISTANCE]
[PHANTOMS GROWLING]
GRAY:
What's happening down there?
Nothing we can't handle.
GRAY: Neil, what's your status?
Almost there.
I want you two back inside.
We're fine, sir. Jane is negotiating
with extreme prejudice.
GRAY:
Talk to me, Jane.
No problem here, captain.
Yes! Captain, we are good to go.
[♪♪♪]
Yeah !
[GASPS]
[NEIL GRUNTING]
No!
[WEAPON CLICKING]
GRAY:
Jane, get out of there.
Get out of there now! Go! Jane!
Get the hell out of there!
Jane!
The shield is powered and ready.
Where are you going?
To the cockpit.
The ship is set on autopilot.
We're in countdown to liftoff.
No, wait.
It's too dangerous. Aki !
[DOOR OPENS]
[PHANTOM MOANING]
Over here,
you son of a bitch !
[SCREAMING]
[METAL CREAKS
AND CRASHES]
[PHANTOM GROWLING]
[RYAN GROANS]
Ryan !
Gray, do you read me?
What's happening?
You and Sid are getting
out of here now.
AKI:
No! We can't just leave everyone.
Everyone's dead !
I'm not leaving without you.
GRAY: I'm sorry, but you
don't have a choice.
Goodbye, Aki.
[GROWLING]
Gray, come on !
[GASPS]
[PHANTOMS MOANING
AND WAILING]
[♪♪♪]
[CRYING]
I just. . .
I wish I could believe
they were in a better place.
[GUN CLICKING]
[COMPUTER BEEPING]
[TYPING]
I enlarged the
scanning perimeter
to include an area that we
had previously overlooked.
The impact crater.
That's a strange place
to find the eighth spirit.
Yes, really quite
astonishing.
But nothing could survive
in there except Phantoms.
Precisely.
Which suggests that the
eighth spirit is a Phantom spirit.
I can't explain it at the moment,
but once we get down there
you will understand--
Wait, doctor. That's a one-way trip.
Yes. Yes, I expected
that's how you would
evaluate our chances.
Well, am I wrong?
No, no, no, I agree.
We probably
won't live long enough to extract
the eighth spirit from the crater.
Then why should we
even try it?
Because we don't need
to extract the eighth spirit.
If we can't bring
the final spirit here,
we can go there and complete
the wave inside the crater.
Yes, exactly.
And how do we do that,
exactly?
I can construct a device that
would attach to Aki's
chest plate to gather the
eighth spirit and then. . .
And then what?
And then we wait
and see what happens.
That's it?
That's your plan? We wait
and see what happens?
Yes.
Oh, good.
Well, I got my own plan.
We keep scanning
the surface from orbit,
and maybe we'll find
a compatible spirit
somewhere else.
Aki?
I say we go in.
MAN [OVER RADIO]:
General Hein, you are cleared for
docking through Zero One Alpha.
[♪♪♪]
What caused the barrier
to fail, General Hein?
Ah. I'm afraid it was
only a matter of time
before the Phantoms developed
an immunity to our barriers.
But I am relieved to see that you
and the rest of the council
were able to evacuate
to Houston without incident.
It was a terrible loss
suffered this evening.
The council has reconsidered your
proposal to fire the Zeus cannon.
I see.
We are transmitting
the access codes to you now.
And, general...
best of luck to us all.
Prepare to fire the cannon.
MAN:
The target, sir?
The Phantom crater.
GRAY [OVER RADIO]:
Preparing to drop in three, two, one.
Powering the shield.
Okay, we're over the meteor.
Do you have it in sight,
doctor?
There are so many of them.
Wait.
Yes! I'm tracking the eighth spirit
moving along the crater's surface.
All right.
Now let's take a closer look.
[♪♪♪]
MAN 1:
Ready to fire in three minutes.
MAN 2: Ovo-pacs at maximum.
Transferring plasma flow to auto.
MAN 3:
Counter-thrusters are engaged.
Lox flow de-coupled.
Status is green.
We have something on radar
over the impact site, sir.
It's her.
MAN 3:
Sir?
Just a traitor under
the influence of the enemy.
Continue the countdown.
We'll take them all out
at the same time.
We're closing
on the Phantom.
Contact in 30 seconds.
Target locked.
Ready to fire
on your command.
It's a match ! It's a perfect match !
MAN 1: Target scanners ready, sir.
Fire.
[PHANTOMS WAILING]
[GROWLING]
What was that?
It's the Zeus.
They're firing on the crater.
SID [OVER RADIO]:
Aki, captain, are you all right?
A little shaken. Stand by.
Sid, the eighth spirit
is not on our scanner.
Do you have it?
The eighth spirit
has been destroyed.
What are we going to do now?
Nothing. This mission is over.
We have to get out of here.
SID: Incoming!
[BOTH GRUNTING]
[WIND HOWLING]
[GROWLING AND SNARLING]
[AKI GASPS]
What is that?
If you're gonna get us out
of here, you better do it now.
[PHANTOM GROWLING]
Hold on !
[BOTH GRUNT]
SID:
Black Boa to Quatro,
I can't hold on to you.
Unable to maintain altitude.
[AKI PANTING]
SID:
Emergency landing procedures.
[PHANTOMS GROWLING
AND WAILING]
SID:
Come in. Come in, please.
Aki, Gray, can you hear me?
Sid, I need to talk to the station.
Can you patch us through?
HEIN: What is that thing?
MAN 1: I don't know, sir.
MAN 2:
Incoming message, sir.
General Hein, you must
cease fire immediately.
What you are looking at
in the crater is the living spirit
of an alien's home world.
Their planet was destroyed
and part of it landed here.
This is not an invasion.
It never was.
Oh, I see. And what have
we been fighting all this time,
doctor? Ghosts?
Yes. Spirits that are confused,
lost and angry.
Oh, right. And these spirits are
coming out of this Gaia thing.
General Hein,
you have to listen.
Alien Gaia, Earth Gaia.
Doctor, even if I believed
in such nonsense,
the fact remains the Earth is
under attack from an aggressor
who must be destroyed
at all costs.
The cost may be
the entire planet, sir.
Firing on the alien Gaia
will only make it stronger.
Well, since you are under
the alien's influence, doctor,
I will take your protest to mean
that we are in fact pursuing
the correct course of action.
So I suggest you take
your last few moments and
prepare to meet your Gaia.
Continue to fire until
the invader has been
destroyed.
[♪♪♪]
[GROWLING]
[SHRIEKING]
[PHANTOM GROWLING
AND SNARLING]
General, the system
is overheating, sir.
We're going to hit it again and again,
and keep on hitting it until it's dead.
But, sir, we're not even
sure if it's having any
effect on the creature.
No effect? We've got them
on the run, soldier.
This is our moment of victory.
I order you to fire.
The system won't
allow us to fire again.
We'll see about that.
Our shield is out.
We're sitting ducks
in here. Come on !
[DOOR OPENS]
[♪♪♪]
[GROWLING NEARBY]
[GROWLING]
This is not a good place to be.
What the hell is that?
That's not what I think
it is, is it?
Yes, it's Gaia.
This is definitely not
a good place to be.
Hey. Are you all right?
I'm fine.
I have to talk to Dr. Sid.
[♪♪♪]
[GROANS]
AKI [OVER RADIO]:
Sid, do you read me?
Go ahead, I'm still here.
We're looking at Gaia.
Do you hear me, Sid? Gaia.
I think this explains why
the eighth spirit appeared here.
Yes.
Yes, that's it!
A Phantom must have changed
into the eighth spirit
when it touched a new life
born from our own Gaia.
If so, it would've been given
a different energy signature
that set it apart from
the other Phantoms.
You two could not have
hoped for a better location
to find a new compatible spirit.
Whatever you do, don't move.
Stay right where you are.
Staying right where we are
may not be as easy as it sounds.
SID:
Don't shoot any of them!
You could very well
destroy our last hope.
Then what do you suggest I do,
doctor? Ask them to play nice?
Combat strategy is your area
of expertise, captain, not mine.
I have a reading here in the
fissure. Do you see it?
Yes! A compatible spirit.
It must be very near you.
Well?
Which one is it?
Which one?
SID: I'm having difficult narrowing
it down. Just a moment, please.
[PHANTOMS GROWLING]
Doctor, it's getting crowded in here.
Aki, we don't have much time. Aki.
GRAY [OVER RADIO]:
Aki.
[GRUNTING]
AKI:
With the hope of new life,
has Gaia changed
the Phantom within?
I have it.
[♪♪♪]
[BEEPS]
AKI [OVER RADIO]:
Gray, get in here. I need you!
Do you hear me, Sid?
The wave pattern is complete.
Yes, I read you.
This is wonderful.
I don't see how you could
have found the final spirit.
It found me, doctor.
Oh, my word.
I see now.
I understand.
Well, I don't understand !
What the hell is going on?
Give me your ovo-pac. I need
to project the completed wave.
But we'll be defenseless.
Just do it!
I hope you know
what you're doing, Aki.
We can use the shield
to project the wave.
What?
Dr. Sid's theory was right.
I have it. The eighth spirit.
I'm cured, Gray.
Are you sure you
have the final spirit?
Yes, yes, I'm sure.
But how? How can you know that?
Don't worry. A Phantom told me.
Oh, great.
That's it. Shield on.
[PHANTOMS GROWLING]
It's not working. We have to do
something before it's too late.
If this doesn't work,
then it's already too late.
Gray.
Trust me.
[♪♪♪]
I'll blast you all to hell.
Oh, no. No!
GRAY:
Get down !
COMPUTER:
Warning. System overload.
HEIN:
I know.
Warning. System overload.
I know!
But it must be done.
Fire.
Fire, damn you !
Fire!
[WAILING]
[♪♪♪]
Gray?
Gray.
[BOTH GRUNTING]
Don't leave me, Gray.
Told Sid this was
a one-way trip.
Looks like I was right.
No, Gray. Hang on, please.
I still have the wave.
We can get through this.
We're not gonna make it.
We're going to make it.
We both know that isn't true.
[PHANTOMS MOANING]
Gray.
Help me.
Gra--
Listen to me.
You saved my life once.
Now I want you to save
yourself.
Gray, no. Please?
Let me do this, Aki.
Trust me.
Don't leave me, Gray.
You've been trying to tell me
that death isn't the end.
Don't back out on me
now that I finally believe.
I love you.
[♪♪♪]
[GASPS]
Oh, it's warm.
[BIRD SCREECHING]
[LARA FABIAN'S
"THE DREAM WITHIN" PLAYING]
[L'ARC-EN-CIEL'S
"SPIRIT DREAMS INSIDE" PLAYING]